Finding aid for the Octavia Broske and George Bancroft Papers LSC.2311
UCLA Library Special Collections
Octavia Broske and George Bancroft Papers
1906-1927
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.2311
0.8 Linear Feet (1 box and 1 flat box)
Octavia Broske and George Bancroft were stage and screen actors in the early 1900s. The collection consists of newspaper clippings and ephemera related to their careers, with the bulk relating to Octavia Broske.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Richard Jones and Joan Jones, 2016
General
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9981682863606533
Biographical/Historical note
Octavia Broske was born circa 1886, in Pennsylvania. She was an actress of both stage and silent film during the early 1900s. She was married to actor George Bancroft. She appeared on stage in a number of cities across the US including Boston, Chicago, Philadelphia, New York, and San Francisco, among others. Her stage credits include Belle of New York, Prince of Pilsen, Sultan of Sulu, Tillie's Nightmare, and A Waltz Dream, among others. She also appeared in silent films, including: The Great Adventure and She Loves and Lies. Octavia Broske died in 1967.
George Bancroft was born in Philadelphia, PA on September 30, 1882. He was educated at Annapolis. He began his stage career as black face entertainer in minstrel shows, eventually going on to act in New York stage dramas and musical comedies such as Ave Maria and Underworld. He made his screen debut in 1921 appearing in The Journey's End. Bancroft was often cast as a villian and/or tough good guys. His film credits include Angels with Dirty Faces (1938), The Docks of New York (1928), Mr. Deeds Goes to Town (1936), Old Ironsides (1926), The Pony Express (1925), Stagecoach (1939), and Underworld (1927). He retired from acting in 1942 to become a rancher. George Bancroft died in 1956.
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of material related to the careers of actors Octavia Broske and George Bancroft. The bulk of the collection is newspaper clippings documenting Broske's stage performaces including The Belle of New York, Florodora, The Folies Beregere, Girls Will Be Girls, Prince of Pilsen, Sultan of Sulu, and Tillie's Nightmare. Additionally, there are clippings representing Bancroft's work in Ave Maria and Underworld, and a very small amount of ephemera, and photographs.
Actors -- United States -- Archives.; Bancroft, George -- Archives; Broske, Octavia -- Archives
- Octavia Broske biographical information, (1906, 1913, 1921, and undated) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Content
  Holographic notes, photographs of daughter, Georgette Octavia Bancroft (2 items), divorce decree from George Burke, and clippings.
- Octavia Broske assorted projects clippings, (1909, 1911, and undated) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Blue Moon, Florodora, The Folies Bergere, The Garden of Melody, The Girl From Paris, Girls Will Be Girls, Jack and the Beanstalk, Mayor of Tokio, and The Politicians.
- Ave Maria clippings, (1921 March-April) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Featuring Bancroft. Mention of daughter, Georgette Octavia Bancroft. Notes from Norbert Lusk.
- The Belle of New York clippings, (1909) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Featuring Broske.
- Mary clippings, (1921) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Featuring Broske. With notes from Chamberlin Brown (agency) regarding commission, and a note on Montgomery Ward stationery regarding performance (signature cannot be deciphered).
- Prince of Pilsen clippings, (1907) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Sultan of Sulu clippings, (1906) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Featuring Broske. With photograph of Helen Rockefeller, Effie Hasty, Mattie Rinenburg, and Octavia Broske.
- Sultan of Sulu clippings scrapbook, (1906) (Box 2)
- Tillie's Nightmare clippings, (1909-1910) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Featuring Broske. With playbill for an appearance at the Cincinnati Pen and Pencil Club.
- A Waltz Dream clippings, (1908-1909) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Underworld mentions in publications, (1927 September-October) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Featuring Broske. The Film Spectator, Harrison's Reports, and Paramount Studio News. One issue of The Film Spectator does not appear related to George Bancroft or Octavia Broske.
- George Bancroft, (1921 March-April) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Receipt from Edward Small, note from H. H. Wentworth, and unidentified receipts.
- Broske and Bancroft vaudeville, (1917) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  With mention about Oh! Oh! Delphine! and note from Bud Fischer.
- Printed ephemera, (1920, undated) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Printed image of unidentified women selling Christmas seals, canceled check signed by Octavia Bancroft, postcard addressed to Octavia Broske, business cards from others, and three Christmas cards. Christmas cards include one item from and two items to George and Octavia, one of which is from Tom Mix.
- Photographs (3 items), (undated) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  One photograph of Vera inscribed to Octavia, and two photographs of unidentified males.
- Photograph of unidentified man and woman sitting on front steps of a house (1 item), (undated) (Box 2)
  Inscribed: 'To our nicest and dearest daughter from [--] and Mama'. Part of the inscription missing due to damage to photograph.
- Orville Harrold debut in Pagliacci clippings, (1910 February) (Box 1, Folder 15)